CARLOS GARCÍA





Cl65B. #88-59 Bogotá D.C

+57-320-702-1833 carlos.grh@outlook.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a 27-year-old professional with over 4 years of experience in account receivable and credit analysis. I am driven through experience and knowledge, always wanting to go above what's expected. My goals are to become a subject matter expert in whatever role I have and obtain results the right way. I am also an excellent team player having received numerous recognition for my work from peers and stakeholders.

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

TECHNICAL SKILL

Public Speaking Patience
Decisiveness Self-starter

Python

VBA

Excel SAP PR1

WORK EXPERIENCE

Strategic Planning Collector

Mar, 2022- Present

Iron Mountain, Bogota D.C

- Handle top sales accounts with risk of suspension portfolio.
- Handle the bi-weekly meeting with the Customer Success Managers and Directors to discuss dispute resolution of high-risk customers.
- Develop and innovate repetitive processes with Python to automize pain points redirecting the focus of tasks for collectors to more impactful analytical processes.
- Project Proposal for with Collections VP, Vertical Manager, and Collections Ops Director for automation through Python of collections communication, mass statements with letters specified for preventive collections, delinquent customers and risk of credit hold.

Credit Service Representative Medtronic SSC, Bogota D.C

Sep, 2019 - Mar, 2022

- Review/create account general information to avoid duplicate accounts for billing/shipping errors.
- Review financial statements of LATAM accounts to suggest a credit limit modification.
- Establish/implement the standard operating procedures for the collections and credit analysis teams.
- Review and implement collection strategies to reduce past due AR.
- Review blocked orders and provide solutions to customer disputes.
- Maintain good customer contact relationship for preventive collections.
- Work collectively with the sales team in order to obtain payment from difficult customers and avoid suspensions/credit holds.
- Initially handled the Endovenous West portfolio and later the Government portfolio with a total of over 15M USD each.
- Developed SAP PRI Scripts integrated with Excel VBA in order to automize invoice download.

Credit and Collections Associate

Stanley Black & Decker Inc, Medellin

- Handle and take ownership of two portfolios, an international-based customer portfolio Xmark from Stanley Black & Decker, and a healthcare-based portfolio Stanley Healthcare Solutions, in total for a portfolio over 10M USD.
- Review and implement collection strategies to reduce past due AR.
- Review blocked orders, provide solutions to customer disputes, review credit limit excess for orders and write up necessary credit limit review for orders that overflow the current customer credit limit.
- Maintain good customer contact relationships for preventive collections.
- Work collectively with the sales team in order to obtain payment from difficult customers and avoid suspensions/credit holds.

Collections Representative

Jan, 2017- Mar, 2018

Nov, 2018 - Jun, 2019

Vohra Wound Physicians, Medellin

- Handle B2C collections for deductible and co-insurance amounts.
- Call customers to ensure they are aware of any past due debts.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

100 days of code: The Complete Python Pro Bootcamp 2022 Udemy

Feb, 2022- Apr, 2022

- PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab
- Python Scripting and Automation
- Web Scraping
- Beautiful Soup
- Selenium Web Driver
- Request
- WTForms
- Python GUI Desktop App Development
- Tkinter
- Front-End Web Development
- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Bootstrap 4

- Bash Command Line
- Git, GitHub and Version Control
- Backend Web Development
- Flask
- REST
- APIs
- Databases
- SQL
- SQLite
- PostgreSQL
- Authentication
- Web Design
- Deployment with GitHub Pages, Heroku and GUnicorn

REFERENCES

Edward Mojica | Credit & Collections Manager at Medtronic Cell: +57 321 2158866 Email: edward.mojica@medtronic.com

Carlos Borja | Model Design and Best Practices Manager at Scotiabank Cell: +57 301 2812329 Email: carlosb.urz@gmail.com